<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Advice on Blog | Albert</title>
    <link>/categories/advice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Advice on Blog | Albert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/advice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Clearing Out Space in My Macbook</title>
      <link>/post/clearing-out-space-in-my-macbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/clearing-out-space-in-my-macbook/</guid>
      <description>Annoying alert that disk space is running low (2-3 GB left of memory!) Checking mac storage - manage, removed some applications I rarely use (only bought me a few GB). But it unhelpfully tells me that 60GB was in “System.” To find out what is in System, use utility called Disk Inventory X and discovered some things I still have old R version 3.4 and 3.5 (a few GB) the MacTex distribution takes up a lot of space (in addition to the 2016 version, I even still had the old versions 2014, 2015).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should You Get a PhD (in biostatistics)?</title>
      <link>/post/should-you-get-a-phd-in-biostatistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/should-you-get-a-phd-in-biostatistics/</guid>
      <description>Throughout the process of applying to graduate school, I felt unsure about whether getting a PhD was a good idea. I remember Googling “should I get a PhD” just to see what I could find out of curiosity. Chances are, if you’re reading this post, you’re in a similar boat. As a now second-year PhD student in biostatistics, I think I have a better idea of whether being in a PhD program has been a good choice for me and I’ll share what I think would’ve been useful for me to know back when I was applying.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>