<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog | Albert</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Blog | Albert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to SQL (for an R user)</title>
      <link>/post/introduction-to-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/introduction-to-sql/</guid>
      <description>Although SQL is commonly used in industry, it’s not something that’s often used or taught in academia. I learned it on my own a few years ago, but since I don’t use it regularly, it’s hard to retain. To resolve this, I’ve created the following guide for basic SQL commands along with their equivalents in R/dplyr. Hopefully, this will allow me to pick it back up again more quickly in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probability of Winning an NBA Game: A Minute-by-Minute Breakdown</title>
      <link>/post/probability-of-winning-an-nba-game-a-minute-by-minute-breakdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/probability-of-winning-an-nba-game-a-minute-by-minute-breakdown/</guid>
      <description>Your NBA team is down 17 points and there are only 8 minutes left in the game. What is the probability that they pull a comeback and win the game?
It’s possible to answer this using historical data (i.e. in the past, how many teams have won after being in this situation). Given that sports commentators love to provide super specific, seemingly arbitrary statistics (e.g. no team has won Game 7 of an ECF after losing Game 6 by more than 10 points), I knew that I should be able to access the relevant data somewhere and calculate these probabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice for Prospective PhD Students (in biostatistics)</title>
      <link>/post/advice-for-prospective-phd-students-in-biostatistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/advice-for-prospective-phd-students-in-biostatistics/</guid>
      <description>It’s application season for graduate admissions again! As a current PhD student, I thought I would share some advice for prospective students. I’d previously written on whether you should get a PhD. In this post, I will talk about things you can do to prepare for a biostatistics PhD and the application process. As with any advice I give on this blog, it is based on my personal experience – I was a math and statistics major in undergrad at UChicago and I’m now a biostatistics PhD student at Johns Hopkins – so your mileage may vary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiences as a Senior PhD Student</title>
      <link>/post/experiences-as-a-senior-phd-student/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/experiences-as-a-senior-phd-student/</guid>
      <description>Today, I wanted to write about the transition from the early stages to the later stages of a biostatistics PhD program and talk more about my experience. Currently, I’m in my 4th year of the biostats PhD program at Johns Hopkins, which means that I have about 1-2 years left in my (5-year) program. I’ve touched upon some of what being a PhD student is like in a previous post, but I think an “update” is due because the day-to-day experience does change quite dramatically as you progress in your PhD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Effect of Increasing Voter Turnout in the U.S.?</title>
      <link>/post/effect-of-increasing-voter-turnout-in-the-u-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/effect-of-increasing-voter-turnout-in-the-u-s/</guid>
      <description>On campaign trails across the U.S., the same message is often repeated: vote! Their goal is to encourage more people to vote, especially the people who are likely to vote for them. But which party benefits more from increasing overall voter turnout? The conventional wisdom today is that it benefits the Democratic party more than the Republican party. This is based on the working knowledge that young people of color are believed to have lower voting turnouts and are also more likely to vote for Democratic candidates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Use Vim</title>
      <link>/post/learning-to-use-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/learning-to-use-vim/</guid>
      <description>Even though vim has been my default text editor for a couple of years now, I’m still woefully ignorant about how to actually use it. Because 95% of my coding time is spent in RStudio, I really only use vim to briefly edit some bash scripts and therefore my unfamiliarity with it isn’t an urgent issue. Nonetheless, I tried to rectify this shortcoming a few months ago by changing my RStudio settings to “vim mode” and forcing myself to use vim commands all the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Preliminary Oral Exam</title>
      <link>/post/my-preliminary-oral-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/my-preliminary-oral-exam/</guid>
      <description>In my PhD program, we are required to take a “preliminary oral exam.” It’s the second major hurdle to getting your PhD, the first being the written comprehensive exam and the last being the thesis defense, and it typically takes place during your third year.
The structure of the oral exam is the following. First, I was asked to leave the room for a few minutes as the committee members decide what order they’re going to ask questions and other logistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Regular Expressions (regex) in R</title>
      <link>/post/introduction-to-regular-expressions-regex-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/introduction-to-regular-expressions-regex-in-r/</guid>
      <description>If you haven’t used regular expressions (regex) before, they are basically a way to write search patterns for strings. I’ve always found them to be inscrutable and unintuitive, so even though the search pattern I have in mind is usually very simple and should, in theory, require only a basic regex, I always have to Google what the correct syntax is. Today, I’m going to try to solve this problem by writing my own guide to regex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clearing Out Space in My Macbook</title>
      <link>/post/clearing-out-space-in-my-macbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/clearing-out-space-in-my-macbook/</guid>
      <description>Annoying alert that disk space is running low (2-3 GB left of memory!) Checking mac storage - manage, removed some applications I rarely use (only bought me a few GB). But it unhelpfully tells me that 60GB was in “System.” To find out what is in System, use utility called Disk Inventory X and discovered some things I still have old R version 3.4 and 3.5 (a few GB) the MacTex distribution takes up a lot of space (in addition to the 2016 version, I even still had the old versions 2014, 2015).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating an R Package (for the first time!)</title>
      <link>/post/creating-an-r-package-for-the-first-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/creating-an-r-package-for-the-first-time/</guid>
      <description>There are already a lot of great resources1 that teach you how to make an R package. But I thought it would still be worthwhile to walk through how I created my first one – at the very least, it’ll be helpful for myself when I write my next R package.
Here is my step-by-step guide to building a (minimally functional) R package.
Step 1: Set up your packages and directory To create your own R package, you will need to use two packages, devtools and roxygen2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started-with-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-started-with-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>I often use R Markdown for my research projects or any kind of data analysis (if you’re familiar with Python, they are similar to Jupyter notebooks). There are many advantages to using R Markdown over writing R scripts. One of the major ones is the ease with which it allows me to turn my work into something presentable for my advisor or other collaborators. By using R Markdown, I don’t have to track down a bunch of plots and files or really do any additional work to organize them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First JSM</title>
      <link>/post/my-first-jsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/my-first-jsm/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I attended JSM (Joint Statistical Meetings) in Denver. It was my first conference ever, so I made sure to record down my thoughts. Since I wasn’t presenting at this conference, I had the luxury of being able to attend sessions without feeling anxious. And that was really great because I think getting to see what conferences are like before I present at one makes it less intimidating. However, going to talks can also be an exhausting experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Few of My Favorite R Packages</title>
      <link>/post/a-few-of-my-favorite-r-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/a-few-of-my-favorite-r-packages/</guid>
      <description>I just finished my second year in the PhD program, which means 2 years of writing a lot of R code. Today, I wanted to share some useful (and perhaps lesser known) R packages that I use.
pacman for loading packages:  This package contains an awesome function called p_load. I prefer the concise way it lets you load packages, as opposed to writing library(package) over and over again. Moreover, p_load automatically checks if you have installed the package and if you haven’t, installs it for you from CRAN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Tips and Tricks for Statistical Proofs</title>
      <link>/post/tips-and-tricks-for-statistical-proofs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/tips-and-tricks-for-statistical-proofs/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been taking probability theory this year and I noticed that a lot of proofs will assume that the reader already knows some commonly used “tricks.” If you aren’t familiar with them, it can be hard to follow the proofs in the textbook,1 let alone prove it yourself. I felt like this was happening to me a lot, so in an effort to better familiarize myself, I’ve written down some useful tips and tricks, along with explanations and/or examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should You Get a PhD (in biostatistics)?</title>
      <link>/post/should-you-get-a-phd-in-biostatistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/should-you-get-a-phd-in-biostatistics/</guid>
      <description>Throughout the process of applying to graduate school, I felt unsure about whether getting a PhD was a good idea. I remember Googling “should I get a PhD” just to see what I could find out of curiosity. Chances are, if you’re reading this post, you’re in a similar boat. As a now second-year PhD student in biostatistics, I think I have a better idea of whether being in a PhD program has been a good choice for me and I’ll share what I think would’ve been useful for me to know back when I was applying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Favorite Books to Date</title>
      <link>/post/my-favorite-books-to-date/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/my-favorite-books-to-date/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes get requests for book recommendations, so I decided to write a post on my favorite books.1 For each book, I give a very short description (&amp;lt; 3 sentences) of the book and why I enjoyed it. Hopefully, that’ll give you some idea of whether you want to read it too.
A quick plug: you might also be interested in following the books I read with my friend Kevin on our reading blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Point Shape Options in ggplot</title>
      <link>/post/point-shape-options-in-ggplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/point-shape-options-in-ggplot/</guid>
      <description>I’m familiar enough with ggplot that I can make a quick plot pretty easily in most cases.1 But when it comes to fine-tuning the various plot aesthetics, like adjusting the legend position or rotating axis tick labels, I always have to look them up. Today, I will be writing about one of these pesky things: looking up the point shape options for geom_point. The available documentation for this isn’t great, so I thought it would be worthwhile to write my own reference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submitting Parallel Jobs on a Cluster</title>
      <link>/post/submitting-parallel-jobs-on-a-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/submitting-parallel-jobs-on-a-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I’ve been running simulations on our school’s computing cluster (JHPCE), which schedules jobs using the Open Grid Engine. Each simulation takes about half a day to complete, so I could run them sequentially and wait a week to get 14 simulation points. Or I could run them in parallel and get 14 simulation points in less than a day!
In theory, running my simulations in parallel should be a very straightforward task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 13:42:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Albert Kuo and I am a PhD student in biostatistics at Johns Hopkins University. To learn more about me, visit my website.
This blog was created with Hugo and blogdown. The theme is based on Sam by Vicky Lai.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up My Blog: Why I Chose Hugo Over Jekyll</title>
      <link>/post/setting-up-my-blog-why-i-chose-hugo-over-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/setting-up-my-blog-why-i-chose-hugo-over-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been reading a lot of people’s blogs in the statistics/data science world lately and it made me start thinking about things that I wanted to write about and share. So here we are – my first post! Hello world!
Before I could write anything, I had to decide on how I was going to build and host the blog. For my personal website, I already use Jekyll, so it seemed natural to build my blog as part of my website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>new? start here</title>
      <link>/new/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/new/</guid>
      <description>I blog about whatever I think would be of interest to my field (biostatistics) and current position (PhD student).
This includes various guides/tutorials on things I&amp;rsquo;m learning, like using R Markdown, writing an R package, and running parallel jobs on a cluster.
For advice on the PhD program, I&amp;rsquo;ve written about whether you should get a PhD, what you can do to prepare, and how my preliminary oral exam went.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>