<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog | Albert</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Blog | Albert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating an R Package (for the first time!)</title>
      <link>/post/creating-an-r-package-for-the-first-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/creating-an-r-package-for-the-first-time/</guid>
      <description>There are already a lot of great resources1 that teaches you how to make an R package. But I thought it would still be worthwhile to walk through how I created my first one – at the very least, it’ll be helpful for myself when I write my next R package.
Here is my step-by-step guide to building a (minimally functional) R package.
Step 1: Set up your packages and directory To create your own R package, you will need to use two packages, devtools and roxygen2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started-with-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-started-with-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>I often use R Markdown for my research projects or any kind of data analysis (if you’re familiar with Python, they are similar to Jupyter notebooks). There are many advantages to using R Markdown over writing R scripts. One of the major ones is the ease with which it allows me to turn my work into something presentable for my advisor or other collaborators. By using R Markdown, I don’t have to track down a bunch of plots and files or really do any additional work to organize them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First JSM</title>
      <link>/post/my-first-jsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/my-first-jsm/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I attended JSM (Joint Statistical Meetings) in Denver. It was my first conference ever, so I made sure to record down my thoughts. Since I wasn’t presenting at this conference, I had the luxury of being able to attend sessions without feeling anxious. And that was really great because I think getting to see what conferences are like before I present at one makes it less intimidating. However, going to talks can also be an exhausting experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Few of My Favorite R Packages</title>
      <link>/post/a-few-of-my-favorite-r-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/a-few-of-my-favorite-r-packages/</guid>
      <description>I just finished my second year in the PhD program, which means 2 years of writing a lot of R code. Today, I wanted to share some useful (and perhaps lesser known) R packages that I use.
pacman for loading packages:  This package contains an awesome function called p_load. I prefer the concise way it lets you load packages, as opposed to writing library(package) over and over again. Moreover, p_load automatically checks if you have installed the package and if you haven’t, installs it for you from CRAN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Tips and Tricks for Statistical Proofs</title>
      <link>/post/tips-and-tricks-for-statistical-proofs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/tips-and-tricks-for-statistical-proofs/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been taking probability theory this year and I noticed that a lot of proofs will assume that the reader already knows some commonly used “tricks.” If you aren’t familiar with them, it can be hard to follow the proofs in the textbook,1 let alone prove it yourself. I felt like this was happening to me a lot, so in an effort to better familiarize myself, I’ve written down some useful tips and tricks, along with explanations and/or examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should You Get a PhD (in biostatistics)?</title>
      <link>/post/should-you-get-a-phd-in-biostatistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/should-you-get-a-phd-in-biostatistics/</guid>
      <description>Throughout the process of applying to graduate school, I felt unsure about whether getting a PhD was a good idea. I remember Googling “should I get a PhD” just to see what I could find out of curiosity. Chances are, if you’re reading this post, you’re in a similar boat. As a now second-year PhD student in biostatistics, I think I have a better idea of whether being in a PhD program has been a good choice for me and I’ll share what I think would’ve been useful for me to know back when I was applying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Favorite Books to Date</title>
      <link>/post/my-favorite-books-to-date/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/my-favorite-books-to-date/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes get requests for book recommendations, so I decided to write a post on my favorite books.1 For each book, I give a very short description (&amp;lt; 3 sentences) of the book and why I enjoyed it. Hopefully, that’ll give you some idea of whether you want to read it too.
A quick plug: you might also be interested in following the books I read with my friend Kevin on our reading blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Point Shape Options in ggplot</title>
      <link>/post/point-shape-options-in-ggplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/point-shape-options-in-ggplot/</guid>
      <description>I’m familiar enough with ggplot that I can make a quick plot pretty easily in most cases.1 But when it comes to fine-tuning the various plot aesthetics, like adjusting the legend position or rotating axis tick labels, I always have to look them up. Today, I will be writing about one of these pesky things: looking up the point shape options for geom_point. The available documentation for this isn’t great, so I thought it would be worthwhile to write my own reference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submitting Parallel Jobs on a Cluster</title>
      <link>/post/submitting-parallel-jobs-on-a-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/submitting-parallel-jobs-on-a-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I’ve been running simulations on our school’s computing cluster (JHPCE), which schedules jobs using the Open Grid Engine. Each simulation takes about half a day to complete, so I could run them sequentially and wait a week to get 14 simulation points. Or I could run them in parallel and get 14 simulation points in less than a day!
In theory, running my simulations in parallel should be a very straightforward task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 13:42:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Albert Kuo and I am a PhD student in biostatistics at Johns Hopkins University. To learn more about me, visit my website.
This blog was created with Hugo and blogdown. The theme is based on Sam by Vicky Lai.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up My Blog: Why I Chose Hugo Over Jekyll</title>
      <link>/post/setting-up-my-blog-why-i-chose-hugo-over-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/setting-up-my-blog-why-i-chose-hugo-over-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been reading a lot of people’s blogs in the statistics/data science world lately and it made me start thinking about things that I wanted to write about and share. So here we are – my first post! Hello world!
Before I could write anything, I had to decide on how I was going to build and host the blog. For my personal website, I already use Jekyll, so it seemed natural to build my blog as part of my website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>new? start here</title>
      <link>/new/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/new/</guid>
      <description>I blog about whatever I think would be of interest to my field (biostatistics) and position (graduate student).
This includes guides/tutorials on things I&amp;rsquo;m learning as a PhD student, like using R Markdown, creating an R package, and running parallel jobs on a cluster.
I&amp;rsquo;ve also written about my favorite books and R packages.
But since my blog is still young, I haven&amp;rsquo;t written very many posts in total. So if you are just browsing, feel free to head on over to posts and see if any of the titles interest you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>